<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Jorgensen</title>
    <link>http://andrewjorgensen.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andrew Jorgensen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewjorgensen.com&#34;&gt;Andrew Jorgensen&lt;/a&gt; 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:57:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewjorgensen.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir ExUnit.DocTest</title>
      <link>http://andrewjorgensen.com/elixir-doctests/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:57:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andrewjorgensen.com/elixir-doctests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been frustrated by the lack working examples in documentation? &lt;a href=&#34;http://elixir-lang.org/&#34;&gt;Elixir&lt;/a&gt; helps solve this problem with a built in feature called DocTest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elixir&amp;rsquo;s testing framework ExUnit provides built in support for a feature called &lt;a href=&#34;http://elixir-lang.org/docs/stable/ex_unit/ExUnit.DocTest.html&#34;&gt;DocTest&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to write test cases in the documentation block for a function. This works really well for pure functions that simply take data and return data but is not advised for any functions that have side effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;defmodule Calculator do
  @doc &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
  Adds two numbers and returns the result.

  ## Examples
      iex&amp;gt; Calculator.add(1, 2)
      3

      iex&amp;gt; Calculator.add(5, 5)
      10
  &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
  def add(a, b) do
    a + b
  end

  @doc &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
  Subtracts two numbers and returns the result.

  ## Examples
      iex&amp;gt; Calculator.subtract(1, 2)
      -1

      iex&amp;gt; Calculator.subtract(5, 5)
      0
  &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
  def subtract(a, b) do
    a - b
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run the test suite, ExUnit will look for these tests then run and verify the results just like if you had written a standard unit test in a specific test module. Now the documentation for the module includes these examples making it really easy for someone to see how the function works without having to dig into the test code or use trial and error to figure out how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;iex&amp;gt; h Calculator.add

                                 def add(a, b)

Adds two numbers and returns the result.

Examples

┃ iex&amp;gt; Calculator.add(1, 2)
┃ 3
┃
┃ iex&amp;gt; Calculator.add(5, 5)
┃ 10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://elixirschool.com/lessons/basics/documentation/#documenting-functions&#34;&gt;Elixir School&lt;/a&gt; also provides some great information on function documentation and the features that Elixir provides.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog</title>
      <link>http://andrewjorgensen.com/hello-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 21:33:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andrewjorgensen.com/hello-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to start this blog at least 20 times over the past few years so here we go&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I&amp;rsquo;d start with all the easy stuff, the stuff I knew I was good at. I&amp;rsquo;d search for a sweet template and then painstakingly tweak all the things about it I didn&amp;rsquo;t like, read blog posts about writing a blog (how meta), make sure git was setup properly and I had an easy way to deploy the site to Github. Then I&amp;rsquo;d reach a sticking point, all that upfront work squandered because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to write about. That and I&amp;rsquo;m also a chronic procrastinator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The secret of getting ahead is getting started.&amp;rdquo; -Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I am, getting started. My hope for this blog is to serve as a living document of my journey with software development, entrepreneurship, and probably a smörgåsbord of other interesting topics that come up along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you expect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short answer is, I have no idea. Longer answer is it will probably be a collection of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned related, but not limited to, topics like vim, elixir, java, and related best practices. My hope is that others will find at least some of these posts interesting and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy and feel free to reach out to me on Twitter, Github, or anywhere else on the interwebs!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>